Siddhartha Majji

Qujarat, India siddharthamajji@gmail.com 9666955112 https://www.linkedin.com/in/siddhartha-majji-060348b1/

SUMMARY

Process Excellence manager with 4 years of experience in Operations, Supply Chain and Production. Demonstrated success in NPD (new product development) and implementing lean concepts to increase efficiency and production output in manufacturing industry. Proven ability to drive and motivate a team to accomplish goals.

Key SKILLS

Capacity PlanningS&OP	New Product Development (NPD)Project Management	Bill Of Operations, Bill of MaterialsKanban System
 Value Stream Mapping (VSM) 	 SOP's and Work Instructions 	Lean Tools
Cycle Time Study	 Industrial Engineering 	

Tools & Technologies

• FMEA	SAP by Design	Lean Problem Solving
Power BI	 Visio 	Six Sigma
Excel VBA	• JDA	

EXPERIENCE

Deputy Manager Hilti Manufacturing India

June 2020 - Present, Gujarat

- Leading the Capacity Planning worth 1.7 M USD/month for the entire manufacturing unit.
- Project Manager: Lead New Product Development (NPD) project worth \$310K for the diamond inserts product.
- Driving the Pre-SNOP & SNOP meetings with different cross functionals teams and stakeholders and project the results to the BU leaders.
- Spearheaded the **procurement** of new machinery worth INR 1.2 Cr to match the business demand using the **Rolling Forecast**.
- Administered the implementation of **JDA platform** to **automate** the **production planning** process, saving around 23% of the supply planning time.
- Digitalization: Automated Overall Equipment Efficiency (OEE) feature using Power BI to save 810 Man hours per month by processing the data and converting into smart Dashboards.
- Continuous Improvement: Worked on water consumption reduction using A3 problem solving approach which saved 5 Million INR.
- Optimizing the process costs through capacity enhancement projects like value stream mapping and increasing the net output.
- Drive the implementations of Lean tools, digitalization projects and visual management through trainings, mentoring and audits.
- Reduced Muda (non-value-added activities) during movement of goods from 42 meters to 29 meters achieving 31% reduction in time.

Analyst

Resource Square Solutions (Deloitte Support Services India Ltd.)

September 2016 - July 2017, Hyderabad

- Best Performance Award for building an innovative tool which solved the time taken to draft an offer letter by 76%.
- Bridged the gap between Human Resources and Technology during the migration of Taleo to RPA for the offer letter generation.

Technology Analyst

GreyCampus Edutech Pvt. Ltd

April 2015 - September 2016, Hyderabad

- Maintained the E-mail servers to fulfil 100% delivery target of the promotional campaigns and to achieve maximum subscriptions for the courses.
- Configured postfix and dovecot for the servers to run the email campaigns and converting them from lead to a successful sale.

PROJECTS

Winter Intern

Taj Hotels • December 2019 - March 2020

• Reduced 8 minutes of waiting time per customer during the weekend breakfast buffet by changing the process flow using Lean Principles.

Summer Interr

Hilti Manufacturing India Pvt. Ltd • April 2019 - June 2019

• Programmed a Predictive Maintenance website with QR Code feature for **12 machines** to create a step by step video guide for maintenance trouble shooting.

Project Intern

Sharada Motors • September 2018 - November 2018

- \bullet Identified critical spares and their suppliers and developed a new $2\ bin\ Kanban\ system.$
- Devised a plan for **change management** for the new Kanban system adoption.
- Realized a cost benefit of INR 11 Lakhs per quarter for 7 critical raw material suppliers.

EDUCATION

MBA in Operations & Supply Chain

Symbiosis Institute of Operations Management • Nashik • 2020

B.Tech in Mechanical Engineering

University College of Engineering • Vizianagaram • 2015

CERTIFICATIONS

German Level A1

LetsTalk Academy

Passed the German A1 level certification from LetsTalk Academy

Lean Six Sigma Black Belt

KPMG • 2020

Certified in Lean Six Sigma Black Belt by KPMG

Operations Analytics

SIOM • 2019

Certified in Analytics using R and Power BI

Business Simulation Program

CAPSTONE • 2019